Guide to the Jesse H. Jones Corporate and Property records, 1836-2008 MS 621
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Jesse H. Jones Corporate and Property records
1836-2008
1920-1990
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Jones, Jesse H. (Jesse Holman)
MS 621
253 boxes
This collection comprises the corporate and property records of Jesse H. Jones, as well as research materials for Unprecedented Power by Steven Fenberg. Between 1992 and 1995, Mr. Fenberg and architecual histoian Barrie Scardino processed and organized the collection at the behest of Houston Endowment. After their transfer to Rice Univeristy some adjusments were made to the organization and nomenclature, but most of the structure they imposed remains intact. Significant areas covered in the records include Jone's many business ventures and property developments throughout the 20th century. For a more comprehensive assessment of this material, Fenberg's original introduction is included below.
Biographical / Historical
Jesse Holman Jones, son of William Hasque Jones and Laura Holman Jones, was born in Robertson County, TN, April 5, 1874. The family soon moved to Dallas, TX, where William Jones managed his brother's lumberyard in Terrell. Two years later the family moved to a farm on the Kentucky-Tennessee border, where after completing ninth grade, Jesse was put in charge of one of his father's tobacco factories. In 1891 Jesse entered Hill's Business College in Dallas and then in 1895 started work at his uncle's firm, the M.T. Jones Lumber Co. in Hillsboro, TX. He soon became manager of the Dallas lumberyard, and upon his uncle's death in 1898 became general manager of the Houston yard. He established his own company, the South Texas Lumber Company and expanded into real estate, banking, and commercial buildings and as the largest developer in the area was responsible for most of Houston's prewar construction of over 100 buildings in Houston, Fort Worth, Dallas, New York City. Between 1908 and 1912 he bought part of Houston Chronicle, became chairman of the Texas Trust Company, president of National Bank of Commerce, an original stockholder in Humble Oil and Refining Company, and as chairman of the Houston harbor board, raised money for the Houston Ship Channel.
During World War I President Woodrow Wilson named him director general of military relief for the American Red Cross, he became sole owner of the Houston Chronicle in 1926, and in 1928 as director of finance for the Democratic National Convention, was instrumental in bringing the convention to Houston. President Herbert Hoover named him to the Reconstruction Finance Coporation, President Franklin Roosevelt appointed him head of the RFC (1933-39) and Federal Loan Administrator (1939), and at the same time became Secretary of Commerce. Jones broke his ties with the Democratic party and returned to Houston in 1945 to concentrate on business ventures and philanthropy. Jones died on June 1, 1956.
Original Introduction and Arrangement
INTRODUCTION In mid-December, 1992, architectural historian Barrie Scardino and I met with Houston Endowment President, Joe Nelson, on the fifth floor of the Bankers Mortgage Building, in what was once Jesse Jones's office. At that time, Ms. Scardino and I were assigned the job of creating an archive from a maze of documents and photographs that had been retrieved from the building's faded green file cabinets, old painted safes and walk-in vaults. Little did we know that the stacks of plain, white bankers boxes arrayed before us were filled with treasures from Houston's past and would reveal rare insight into Mr. Jones's public, business and personal lives. Houston Endowment had recently moved its offices to the Texas Commerce Tower and had emptied Bankers Mortgage Building of its few remaining tenants, leaving behind these remarkable relics for Ms. Scardino and I to organize and preserve. We established a work space in that same fifth floor office, in the vacant, ten story building on Main Street Mr. Jones built back in 1908 for the Texas Company. As the mass of material slowly took form, our awareness of Mr. Jones's philosophies, achievements and contributions also began to emerge. About one year later, we moved the evolving archive to Houston Endowment's new office and went to work in one of the conference rooms. Ms. Scardino completed her portion of the project in May of 1994, and, before leaving, created an index to the archive's personal papers. I remained and continued to work on the Foundation's exhibit, which I began soon after we moved into the new building. In January of 1995, it was decided that similar material, housed in temporary storage, should be included in the collection's corporate and property records. (Folders containing this material have stars on the left corner to distinguish them from the more specifically categorized and refined original material.) Now that this task has been accomplished, the archive is complete. The accompanying indexes are general guides to provide easy access to the collection's documents. The alphabetically listed corporate and property records may not adhere to that arrangement within a box due to the material's varying shapes and sizes. An explanation of certain entries in the corporate and property indexes follows: BOOK OF ACCOUNT--includes ledgers and journals DATES--indicate the age range of documents within each entry, even though they may relate to an event that occurred on a specific date, such as a loan or sale Franchise and income tax dates indicate the years taxes were incurred Gaps in dates indicate missing documents Stock book dates indicate the years during which stock was issued Articles of incorporation dates indicate the day the corporate officers signed the incorporation papers (articles of incorporation sometimes appear as a separate document; may appear in the front of the minute book; or, if there are two or more minute books, may appear with the dissolution certificate in the last book) Dissolution certificate dates indicate the day the state issued the certificate VARIOUS DOCUMENTS--includes contracts, correspondence, deeds, inventories, maps and receipts VARIOUS BUILDINGS, VARIOUS CORPORATIONS, VARIOUS PROPERTIES- Includes documents involving two or more entities In the Texas counties where Mr. Jones conducted significant building programs, the property records have been sub-divided into city blocks with their corresponding buildings. Because Mr. Jones invested primarily in Harris County, the volume and scope of the material dictated that the collection be further divided by leagues, surveys, additions and sub-divisions as well as blocks. Only property records involving New York City are organized by address. This collection embodies a large part of Houston's history. It includes documents involving Stephen F. Austin, the Allen Brothers and, from the more recent past, many notable people, buildings and events. It includes papers from M. T. Jones's vast lumber empire, the business that fueled his nephew Jesse's profound impact on Houston's development and growth. This archive also encompasses the source of one of Mr. Jones's most lasting legacies, Houston Endowment Inc., a legacy that perpetuates his positive influence on our world today. Steven L. Fenberg July 14, 1995
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in this collection are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Jesse H. Jones Corporate and Property records were received on Octorber 10, 2014 from Houston Endowment, Inc.
Related Materials
See also Jesse H. Jones Family and Personal Papers, and M.T. Jones Lumber Co. Records & Business Ledgers; Barker Texas History Center, University of Texas at Austin, and Library of Congress.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series, Series I: Corporate Records II: Property Records III: Research for Unprecendented Power by Steven Fenberg, with sub-series as appropriate.
Index Terms
Subjects
Business enterprises -- Texas -- Houston; City planning -- Texas -- Houston; Business
Document Types
Maps
Places
Texas -- Houston; Texas -- Houston Ship Channel; Houston (Tex.) -- History.; Houston (Texas) -- Buildings, structures, etc.
Subjects (Persons)
Jones, Jesse H. (Jesse Holman)
- Series I: Corporate Records, 206870
  - Alamo Investment Company, 1929-1931; 206871
    - Minute Book, 206872 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 1929; 208421
    - Income Tax Returns, 1930-1931; 206874 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Construction Company, 1917; 206875
    - Various Documents, 1917; 206876 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aqua Pura Bottling Company, 206877
    - Various Documents, 1914; 206878 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Attoyac River Lumber Company, 1913-15; 206879
    - Various Documents, 1913-1915; 206880 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Auditorium Building Company, 206881
    - Articles of Incorporation, 5/22/1901; 206882 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Stock Book, 1901; 206883 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Various Documents, 1901-1909; 206884 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Auditorium Investment Company, 206885
    - Franchise Tax and Income Tax, 1913-1935; 206886 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Minute Book, 1931-1935; 206888 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Chronicle Co. (Houston Chronicle Publishing Co. KTRH Broadcasting Co.), 208950
    - Audit Reports, 1948-1950; 208951 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Audit Reports, 1954-1956; 208952 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Audit Reports, 1956-1957; 209120 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Audit Reports, 1957-1959; 209121 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Audit Reports, 1959-1960; 209122 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Book of Account, 1947-1966; 209124 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Franchise Tax, 1947-1966; 209125 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Income Tax, 1947-1962; 209126 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Income Tax, 1963-1966; 209127 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Indenture of Mortgage and Deed of Trust (I), 1948; 209128 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Indenture of Mortgage and Deed of Trust (II), 1948; 210936 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Indenture of Mortgage and Deed of Trust (III), 1948; 210937 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Liquidated in HEI, 5/31/1966; 209131 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Loan (BL 58), 1948; 209132 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Loan (BL 58), 1948; 209133 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Loan, 1948-1954; 209134 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Loan, 1948-1954; 209135 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Loan, 1948-1954; 209136 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Minute Book, 1947-1966; 209137 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 9/10/1947; 209138
      - Dissolution Certificate, 6/1/1966; 209139
    - Purchase Agreement, 1948; 209140 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Stock Book, 1947; 209141 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Austin and Rusk Realty Company, 206889
    - Book of Account, 1935-1936; 206890 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dissolution Papers, 10/14/1936; 206891 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Income Tax; Franchise Tax, 1919-1936; 1930-1935; 206892 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Minute Book, 1936; 206894 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Stock Book, 1916-1936; 206895 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Various Documents, 1923-1938; 206896 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bankers Mortgage Company (OLD), 206897
    - Articles of Incorporation, 6/9/1923; 206898 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Book of Account, 1927-1950; 208252 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bonds, 1930-1935; 208253 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - H.F. Eaker Loan, 1958-1960; 208254 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Financial Statements, 1962-1973; 208255 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Fanchise Taxes, 1914-1974; 208256 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Franchise Taxes, 1975-1987; 208257 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Income Tax, 1949; 1975-1979; 208258 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Merger into Travis Mortgage Company (I), 12/16/1974; 208259 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Merger into Travis Mortgage Company (II), 12/16/1974; 210938 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Merger into Travis Mortgage Company (III), 12/16/1974; 210939 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Merger into Travis Mortgage Company (IV), 12/16/1974; 210940 (Box 1, Folder 284)
    - Merger into Travis Mortgage Company (V), 12/16/1974; 210941 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Merger into Travis Mortgage Company (VI), 12/16/1974; 210942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Merger into Travis Mortgage Company (VII), 12/16/1974; 210943 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Merger into Travis Mortgage Company (VIII), 12/16/1974; 210944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Notes Receivable, 1927-1961; 208286 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Property Taxes, 1931; 208287 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Property Taxes, 1932; 208288 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Property Taxes, 1933; 208289 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Property Taxes, 1934; 208290 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Property Taxes, 1935; 208291 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Property Taxes, 1936; 208292 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Property Taxes, 1937; 208293 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Property Taxes, 1938; 208294 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Property Taxes, 1939; 208295 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Property Taxes, 1940; 208296 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Property Taxes, 1941; 208297 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Property Taxes, 1942; 208298 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Property Taxes, 1943; 208332 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Property Taxes, 1944; 208333 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Property Taxes, 1945; 208335 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Property Taxes, 1946; 208336 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Property Taxes, 1947; 208337 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Property Taxes, 1948-1949; 208338 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Property Taxes, 1950-1951; 208339 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Property Taxes, 1952-1953; 208388 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Property Taxes, 1954-1955; 208389 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Property Taxes, 1956-1957; 208390 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Property Taxes, 1958-1959; 208391 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Property Taxes, 1960-1961; 208392 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Property Taxes, 1962-1963; 208393 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Property Taxes, 1964-1965; 208394 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Property Taxes, 1966-1967; 208395 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Property Taxes, 1968-1969; 208396 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Property Taxes, 1970-1971; 208397 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Property Taxes, 1972-1974; 208548 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Stock Book, 1924-1934; 208398 (Box 100, Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Stewart Trust Co., 1959-1962; 208399 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - H.B. Tartt Property Mgmt., 1941-1946; 208301 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - 1934 Tax Dispute, 1934-1940; 208302 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Various Documents, 1922-1956; 208303 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Various Documents, 1957-1974; 208304 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Bankers Mortgage Co vs. IRS, 1977-1978; 208305 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Bankers Mortgage Co vs. TEXACO #984464, 1935-1974; 208306 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Bankers Mortgage Co vs. TEXACO #984464, 1977; 208307 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Bankers Mortgage Co vs. TEXACO #984464, 1977-1982; 208308 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - J. Cammack Loan, 1931-1939; 208309 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Capital Stock Tax Reports (includes subsidiaries), 1933-1946; 208310 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Dun and Bradstreet Reports, 1950-1976; 208311 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Minutes Book, 6/9/1923; 208312 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 208424
    - OSHA, 1969-1974; 208313 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Stock, 1941-1974; 208400 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Stockholders, 1940-1968; 208401 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Stockholder's Meeting, 1970-1974; 208402 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Texas Independent Producers and Royalty Owners Association, 1957-1964; 208403 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Texas Unemployment Commission, 1936-1952; 208404 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Texas Unemployment Commission, 1953-1965; 208405 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Texas Unemployment Commission, 1966-1975; 208406 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Withholding Taxes, 1937-1962; 208407 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1959; 208408 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Bankers Trust Co., 208387
    - Eli Howell vs. Bankers Trust, 1914; 208409 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Various Documents, 1909-1929; 208415 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - H.T.D. Wilson, 1912-1914; 208416 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - New York, 1958-1967; 216924 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Bayou Broadcasting Co., 208411
    - Minute Book, 1936-1937; 208412 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 2/7/1936; 208413
      - Dissolution Certificate, 7/23/1937; 208414
    - Stock Book, 1936; 208422 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Various Documents, 1936-1937; 208423 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Bayou City Realty Co., 208419
    - Various Documents, 1913; 208420 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Beck Cattle and Land Co., 208425
    - Various Documents, 1950-1970; 208426 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Birmingham Properties, Inc., 208427
    - Tax Returns, 1929-1934; 208428 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Block Eighty-Nine, Inc., 208429
    - Corporate Names Changed to "Block Eighty Nine, Inc.", 3/25/1936; 208430 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Book of Account, 208431 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Franchise Tax, 1938-1946; 208432 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Income Tax, 1936-1941; 208433 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Income Tax, 1942-1944; 208434 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Minute Book 2, 1939-1945; 208435 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Dissolution Certificate, 12/31/1945; 208436
    - Transfer to Realty Mgmt Co; Notes Receivable, 12/20/1945; 1936; 208549
    - Various Documents (I), 1938; 208550 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Various Documents (II), 1938; 208551 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Block Eighty-Two, Inc., 208526
    - Franchise Tax, 1946-1962; 208527 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Income Tax, 1946-1956; 208528 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Income Tax, 1957-1963; 208529 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Liquidation Into Commerce Co., 9/24/1963; 208530 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Minute Book, 1946-1963; 208531 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 9/12/1946; 208532
    - Minute Book 2, 1963; 208533 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Dissolution Certificate, 10/1/1963; 208534
    - Stock Book, 1946-1963; 208535 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Statements and Receipts, 1952-1956; 208536 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Book of Account, 1951-1954; 208537 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Book of Account, 1945-1963; 208538 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Ledgers, 1945-1951; 208539 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Franchise tax, 1945-1963; 208540 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Income Tax Return, 1945-1953; 208541 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Block Fifty-Seven, Inc., 208542
    - Liquidated into HEI, 9/25/1963; 208543 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Loan- Rice Hotel, 1945-1948; 208544 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Loan- Rice Hotel, 1945-1948; 208545 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Loan- Rice Hotel, 1945-1948; 208546 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Loan- Rice Hotel and Garage, 1948-1953; 208547 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Loan- Rice Hotel and Garage, 1948-1953; 208635 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Loan- Rice Hotel and Garage, 1948-1953; 208636 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Minute Book, 1945-1963; 208637 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 1/29/1945; 208638
      - Dissolution Certificate, 10/1/1963; 208639
    - Stock Book, 1945-1948; 208640 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Block One Thirty Nine, Inc., 208614
    - Book of Account (I), 1941-1953; 208615 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Book of Account (II), 1941-1953; 208616 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Book of Account (III), 1941-1953; 208617 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Book of Account, 1942-1963; 208618 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Book of Account (I), 1945-1964; 208619 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Book of Account (II), 1945-1964; 208620 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Book of Account (III), 1945-1964; 208621 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Book of Account, 1964-1973; 208622 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Books of Account, 208623 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Book of Account, Transfer Journal (I), 1941-1951; 208624 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Book of Account, Transfer Journal (II), 1941-1951; 208625 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Book of Account, Transfer Journal (III), 1941-1951; 208626 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Book of Account (I), 1946-1963; 208627 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Book of Account (II), 1946-1963; 208628 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Book of Account (III), 1946-1963; 208629 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Book of Account, 1950-1955; 208630 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Book of Account, 1963-1973; 208631 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Franchise Tax, 1941-1962; 208632 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Income Tax (I), 1943-1963; 208633 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Income Tax (II), 1943-1963; 208634 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Minute Book, 1946-1963; 208777 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 1941; 208778
    - Minute Book, 1946-1963; 208812 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Dissolution Certificate, 1963; 208813
    - Stock Book, 1941-1945; 208814 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Statements and Receipts, 1943-1957; 208815 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Reports, 1954-1959; 208816 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Liquidated in Commerce Co., 8/6/1963; 208817 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bristol Hotel Co., 208804
    - Statements and Taxes, 1931-1933; 208805 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Minute Book, 1931-1936; 208806 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 3/13/1931; 208807
      - Dissolution Certificate, 10/23/1936; 208808
    - Stock Book, 1931-1936; 208809 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Various Documents, 1910-1919; 208810 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Book of Account, 1934-1948; 208811 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Bristol Realty Co., 208785
    - Franchise Tax, 1930-1964; 208786 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Income Tax, 1914-1929; 208787 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Income Tax, 1930-1943; 208788 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Income Tax, 1944-1963; 208789 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Loan- Block 82: Lots 1, 2, and 3 (1), 1919-1949; 208790 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Loan- Block 82: Lots 1, 2, and 3, 1919-1949; 208791 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Loan, 1952-1955; 208792 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Minute Book, 1914-1935; 208793 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Articles of Incorporaton, 12/3/1914; 208794
    - Minute Book, 1936-1964; 208795 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Dissolution Certificate, 12/9/1964; 208796
    - Stock Book, 1947; 208797 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Various Documents, 1914-1930; 208798 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Bryan Realty Co., 208799
    - Articles of Incorporation, 1909; 208800 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Franchise Tax, 1930-1934; 208801 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Income Tax, 1914-1926; 208802 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Income Tax, 1927-1935; 208803 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Stock Book, 1910-1921; 208920 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Various Documents, 1909-1924; 208921 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - L. Bryan Co., 208887
    - Various Documents, 208888 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - C and I Corporation, 208889
    - Franchise Tax, 1947-1954; 208890 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - J. I. Campbell Co., 208891
    - Articles of Incorporation, 1904; 208892 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - The Warren and Corsicana Pacific RY. Co., 1899-1904; 208893 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Campbell v. Campbell, 1904-1905; 208894 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Tyler County Land and Lumber Co., 1904-1905; 208895 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Various Documents, 1905; 208896 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Captrav Realty Co., 208897
    - Book of Account, 1936-1948; 208898 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Book of Account- Journal, 1944-1948; 208899 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Dissolution Working Papers, 1944-1948; 208900 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 1936-1948; 208901 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Articles of Incorporation; Dissolution Papers, 1936; 1948; 208902 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Stock Certificates, 208903 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Ehibit File- Stock Purchases, 1948; 208904 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Various Documents, 1937-1948; 208905 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Carter Lumber Co., 208906
    - Various Documents, 1913-1914; 208907 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Chamber of Commerce Building Co., 208908
    - Income Tax, 1923-1932; 208909 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Stock Book, 1924; 208910 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Various Documents, 1922-1934; 208911 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Cherry and Burnett Properties, Inc., 208912
    - Book of Account (I), 1947-1951; 208913 (Box 11, Folder 22)